<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Curt Poff</title>
 <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com"/>
 <updated>2016-01-17T22:55:10-08:00</updated>
 <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Curt Poff</name>
   <email>curt.poff@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Slow time of year for sports</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/sports-slow"/>
   <updated>2016-01-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/sports-slow</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The NFL playoffs are down to the final four and my Chiefs are now eliminated. Rough finish to a rough season. Thus begins the slow season for sports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally this time of year I’d turn my attention to Mizzou and Arizona MBB. All this as a lead-up to the NCAA tourney and our annual trip to Las Vegas. But the Tigers are in the crapper (yet again), so it’s down to the Arizona Wildcats to fill my time. I’ve also been following the Trail Blazers but they’re in rebuilding mode. Not much to see there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time college hoops runs its course we’ll have both MLS and MLB back in season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/sports-slow&amp;amp;text=Slow time of year for sports&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; 
and/or 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;
  follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Big trouble in eastern Oregon</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/eastern-oregon"/>
   <updated>2016-01-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/eastern-oregon</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’d like to offer a summary on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oregonlive.com/pacific-northwest-news/index.ssf/2016/01/oregon_standoff.html&quot;&gt;the standoff going on out in the eastern part of Oregon&lt;/a&gt;. It’s complicated but I’ll try to use adequate sourcing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The central figures are a father/son team named Hammond. Dwight Hammond Jr., 73, and Steven Hammond, 46. They were &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.justice.gov/usao-or/pr/eastern-oregon-ranchers-convicted-arson-resentenced-five-years-prison&quot;&gt;convicted of arson&lt;/a&gt; by a jury, sentenced to time, then re-sentenced because the original judge was deemed to be too lenient. Additional claims that they set the blazes in order to conceal vast poaching were also mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arson is a &lt;strong&gt;felony&lt;/strong&gt; and carries a five-year minimum sentence. On Monday the Hammonds reported to a federal prison in California. They committed arson and are doing mandatory five years. End of story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Important to note: The Hammonds were tried by a jury in Pendleton, Oregon. That’s a good ol’ boy Mecca. Not exactly a tree-hugging liberal bastion. I’ve been to the fantastic rodeo up there - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pendletonroundup.com/&quot;&gt;the Pendleton Roundup&lt;/a&gt; - with my parents and I’d recommend to everyone. But make no mistake: There’s no way a government railroad job could pass through a jury of rancher peers. No f*&amp;amp;#!@# way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then recently the ‘militia’ showed up in Burns, led by the Bundys. This is the family &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bundy_standoff&quot;&gt;you may remember from a flare-up&lt;/a&gt; not long ago in Nevada. The family rails against the government and all. It’s fine. But they came to Oregon to support the Hammonds even though no such request was ever made. They just want the attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now they’ve holed up in a federal faciilty outside Burns. They say they’ll stay as long as it takes, alhough no one’s clear what their demands are other than returning all federal land to ranchers. Not sure how that will happen. They’re basically a bunch of anti-government crackpots looking for a spotlight. Hopefully the FBI will quietly cut off their Internet access, deny food, then offer to fill up their gas tanks if they agree to head home. Problem solved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know land disputes between ranchers and the government date all the way back to the beginning of the BLM. I don’t have a dog in that fight. But federal land is maintained for the common good and managed accordingly. Ranchers can graze but can’t exercise absolute control in certain matters (water management, controlled burns, etc.). No way the management of public land will work out perfectly to everyone’s liking. But at least let the government manage range land as best they can. Understand that what’s best for you personally may not necessarily be best for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then this evening I had a lively (but civil) exchange on FB with a good friend and the word ‘terrorism’ came into play. He circulated a petition claiming justice for the Hammonds, who it claimed were convicted of secret terrorism charges. Totally untrue. The claim of terrorism - as noted in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usnews.com/news/us/articles/2016-01-01/oregon-ranching-case-sparks-anti-government-sentiment&quot;&gt;the AP report my friend presented as evidence&lt;/a&gt; - came from an e-mail sent by Ammon Bundy to stir up reactions. Well done, Ammon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The terrorism claim is cloudy to me but appears to be part of the original charge. It’s not entirely clear the way that article is written. Poor news writing, I’ll admit it could be clearer. But still. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Militia_occupation_of_the_Malheur_National_Wildlife_Refuge&quot;&gt;Wikipedia article on this topic&lt;/a&gt; has a better breakdown of the terrorist aspect. It has alot to do with federal property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So with that I’d like to point out that a whole bunch of armed (entirely white) folks have seized a federal facility in the United States in support of an arsonist duo who have alrealdy reported to prison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two questions come from all this. &lt;strong&gt;(Todd, this bit is specifically for you)&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do you really want to throw your support behind two convicted arsonists? If you want justice, I’d first ask you to explain how it has not already been administered.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And how would you react if this occupation of federal property was going on in suburban Kansas City … and the armed folks were black? Would you be so eager to post petitions in support?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s The Oregonian’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://topics.oregonlive.com/tag/showdown%20in%20burns/&quot;&gt;collection of articles&lt;/a&gt;. Feel free to read for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/eastern-oregon&amp;amp;text=Big trouble in eastern Oregon&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; 
and/or 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;
  follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Here&#39;s to a new year</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/new-year"/>
   <updated>2016-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/new-year</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;2015 was a transitional year for me. The lovely wife and I relocated, changed careers, and left a great group of friends and colleagues in the Bay Area. It’s been a challenge, but I’m very excitied about the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go somewhere new and start something new. We both did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann went to work as soon as we arrived in PDX. She started teaching regular indoor cycling and yoga classes at various gyms/studios. It’s been great. She keeps a regular professional schedule and alots time to speak to students. She takes it seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to school. Portland Codes School’s javascript immersion program went three months over the summer. I took the primer class in the spring so I was prepared. I spent the entire autumn and a portion of winter searching for work. I had several good talks but no job offers materialized. I have a couple conversations going now and am very optimistic. Looking forward to getting back to work. Into a regular schedule again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also look forward to traveling again, something we can only do as a dual-income family. Looking forward to picking through the greatest hits when we formulate our Xmas cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope 2016 treats everyone well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/new-year&amp;amp;text=Here&#39;s to a new year&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; 
and/or 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;
  follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Christmas season in full swing</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/lazy-christmas"/>
   <updated>2015-12-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/lazy-christmas</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/cheesemas/&quot;&gt;Cheesemas&lt;/a&gt; went off without a hitch and everyone had a wonderful time. Now it’s time to sit back and enjoy some holiday laziness. Football, binge-watching TV shows, homemade posole. It’s all in the cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was Christmas and we just lounged around the house. Ann and I had our feast the previous night - as is our tradition. Ann taught a yoga workshop in the afternoon, then we went for an evening showing of the new Star Wars movie at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mcmenamins.com/219-bagdad-theater-pub-home&quot;&gt;Baghdad Theatre&lt;/a&gt;. Good times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather has been terrible here. Cold and rainy, but not enough for snow. For now I just take my daily walk when the weather looks suitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight we’re joining another couple for pizza and beers at a new place in Multnomah Village. But for now it’s all football and Game of Thrones (which happens to be airing all previous seasons over the coming days on HBO).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/lazy-christmas&amp;amp;text=Christmas season in full swing&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; 
and/or 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;
  follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cheesemas is here!</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/cheesemas"/>
   <updated>2015-12-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/cheesemas</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This Saturday we’ll host our annual holiday party, also known as Cheesemas. How that party got to this point is a long story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann and I moved to the Bay Area is early 2005. We didn’t know many folks and didn’t have much of a social schedule. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/philipmichaels&quot;&gt;Phil Michaels&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lschmeiser&quot;&gt;Lisa Schmeiser&lt;/a&gt; were recently married and moved to town not long after us. Phil being my boss, we talked frequently and wasn’t long before he and Lisa invited the wife and I over for dinner. We got along great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would go to their Alameda house for three types of events: sports, election coverage, holiday. Phil and I both being baseball and soccer fans, sports was our maintstay. Election coverage was also a good annual treat. I remember watchin both Schwarzenegger’s Calif. governor re-election and Obama’s big win at Casa Schmichaels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Cheesemas was our crown jewel. Our holiday franchise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lisa sent us a holiday invite in 2005/6 for ‘cheesemas.’ We came over, ate cheese, and guzzled adult beverages. Phil and Lisa - both being professional media consumers and reviewers - said they had a horribly fantastic holiday movie that we should watch. Rob Lowe’s ‘The Christmas Shoes’ was queued up and followed by surly, obscene poetry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheesemas has been our primary holiday event ever since. It follows a very rigid agenda: Invite adults to join for cocktails. Everyone brings a cheese-y dish to share. Get everyone primed with a few drinks before we fire up the holiday special for the British clay-mation classic &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_DUf27qvRo0&quot;&gt;Creature Comforts&lt;/a&gt;. All good holiday stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refreshments refilled we move on to the feature presentation. The Christmas Shoes is a horribly predictable and cliché holiday stinker. It’s a movie based on a cheesy holiday song by a Christian rock band. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iq10bz3PxyY&quot;&gt;No joke&lt;/a&gt;. But it’s Rob Lowe’ first project after he left ‘West Wing’ so you know he’s at the height of his carrer, right? No chance. It’s a terrible movie and we spend 90 minutes heckling the entire script and all associated with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phil wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.televisionwithoutpity.com/show/mondo-extra/the-christmas-shoes/&quot;&gt;seminal review&lt;/a&gt; of the film. Well worth reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so goes the story of Cheesemas. This Saturday Ann and I will welcome a new crowd of adults to our Portland home. The location is new, but we hope the long-established and beloved tradition lives on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/cheesemas&amp;amp;text=Cheesemas is here!&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; 
and/or 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;
  follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>I&#39;m all about championships</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/title-town"/>
   <updated>2015-12-07T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/title-town</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m very excited to have been along for TWO championships this year. Lucky me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kcroyals.com&quot;&gt;KC Royals&lt;/a&gt;. You all know my lifelong devotion to the boys in blue. So happy to have been around to see the beginnings of the first small-market baseball dynasty. I’ve been a sports fan my entire life. But I’ve only lived in cities for the World Series title: three in San Fran (2010, ‘12, ‘14) and one in Phoenix (D-Backs 2001). I watched the Royals all year long on MLB.TV.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timbers.com/&quot;&gt;Portland Timbers&lt;/a&gt;. Went to several regular-season games - including a Cascadia Cup battle against Seattle where I sat in the Timbers Army - along with two playoff games. Plus one pre-season game and an exhibition for the T2 reserves against Newcastle Utd. (T2 won easily).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thrilling win over Dallas in the opening leg of the semifinals was really good. But the best part was the shootout against Sporting KC in the single-game playoff. One potential PK winner for KC went off &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; posts before bouncing out and giving new life to the Timbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then yesterday the Timbers were able to cling to an early lead and hang on to win the MLS Cup. First in franchise history and the first top-level championship for Portland since the ‘76 Blazers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m thinking I should be getting a couple calls in the near future from teams (&lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt; Trail Blazers, Oregon Ducks &lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt;) with an offer of free season tickets. Come on, guys. I have the Golden Touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/title-town&amp;amp;text=I&#39;m all about championships&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; 
and/or 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;
  follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New theme for the Jekyll blog</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/new-blog-theme"/>
   <updated>2015-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/new-blog-theme</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I re-installed an advanced version of my Jekyll blog that included a new theme. Hope you find it suitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllbootstrap.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; construction seems well suited for my needs. It has all the social buttons and plug-ins I need. There are about half a dozen stock themes, so don’t be surprised if you see a few of them over the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also let it be know that I’m extremely satisfied running my blog on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. They provide free hosting as long as you don’t require much advanced functionality. The Jekyll platform - which is a static site construction - is lightning fast and extremely secure. And you can’t beat the price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More things to come, I’m sure. But I feel like &lt;a href=&quot;http://curtpoff.com&quot;&gt;my homepage&lt;/a&gt; and blog are starting to take shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; The top nav should now be both responsive and sticky. The only catch is that it isn’t sticky once it collapses. I’ll see if there’s anyway to fix that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/new-blog-theme&amp;amp;text=New theme for the Jekyll blog&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
  share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; 
and/or 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;
  follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New Linux installation on old iMac</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/linux-imac"/>
   <updated>2015-11-27T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/linux-imac</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I installed Ubuntu Linux on an old iMac over the Thanksgiving holiday weekend. Actually, I did most of the work on Thanksgiving day and cleaned it all up today (Friday)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This iMac was built in 2007and has an Intel Core 2 Duo processor. It had been sitting in the closet since we moved back to Oregon because it’s waaaaaay too slow for modern use. Since it was just collecting dust I decided to try &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.howtogeek.com/187410/how-to-install-and-dual-boot-linux-on-a-mac/&quot;&gt;this little experiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I created a Ubuntu live CD (a boot disk) and installed the Re-Fit utility that allows Mac users to choose which OS/disk to boot from. Once I fired it up and booted to the Linux install, I just ran the installer and viola. A fresh and much faster desktop machine I can now use without having to spend a bunch of time watching the spinning beachball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to use the iMac as a media center, duties previously allotted to my Mac mini. The DVD drive on that mini crapped out recently so I was looking for replacements. We’ll see how XBMC and Plex work out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/linux-imac&amp;amp;text=New Linux installation on old iMac&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bootstrap homepage now operational</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/new-homepage"/>
   <updated>2015-11-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/new-homepage</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I now have a valid (and secure) website hosted at &lt;a href=&quot;https://curtpoff.com&quot;&gt;curtpoff.com&lt;/a&gt;. You may also notice that I’ve successfully installed a CNAME record pointing this blog to a subdomain of curtpoff.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure why that took so long but it’s finally finished. I also purchased the cpoff.com domain (thanks for the cheap sale, namecheap.com) and set a permanent redirect to the curtpoff.com site. That page is pretty much a fancy ‘business card’ site built using Bootstrap. There won’t be many updates to the page contents. All updates will continue appear on the blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to keep using the (free!) GitHub Pages/Jekyll system to run the blog. It’s working well and I feel comfortable using it. It also provides all the functionality I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/new-homepage&amp;amp;text=Bootstrap homepage now operational&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Here comes the ham</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/ham-feast"/>
   <updated>2015-11-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/ham-feast</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just participated in another annual tradition, this time with a Thanksgiving twist. I ordered a ham and bacon shipment from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smokehouse.com/&quot;&gt;Burgers Smokehouse&lt;/a&gt; in Missouri.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann and I aren’t really turkey fans and we don’t like the fuss of fixing one for Thanksgiving. So we got in the habit of ordering one of the fantastic country hams from Burgers. It comes &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smokehouse.com/burgers.nsf/item/spiral-sliced-city-ham&quot;&gt;cooked and sliced&lt;/a&gt;, sealed in a vacuum pack. You just have to heat it up for about an hour and it just falls right off the bone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It keeps very well too. Good for leftovers for a couple weeks. Plus you get a big, meaty ham bone when it’s all done. So I may take a crack at a crock pot of ham &amp;amp; beans this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann also like the bacon sampler. They have a variety of bacon varieties so we just get a sampler pack. Here’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smokehouse.com/burgers.nsf/item/sliced-bacon-sampler&quot;&gt;the one&lt;/a&gt; we got this year. Some of you might prefer the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smokehouse.com/burgers.nsf/item/bacon-steak-sampler&quot;&gt;bacon steaks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to the feast next week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/ham-feast&amp;amp;text=Here comes the ham&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Meat on the table</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/hunt-report"/>
   <updated>2015-11-16T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/hunt-report</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I &lt;a href=&quot;/deer-season/&quot;&gt;mentioned earlier&lt;/a&gt;, this weekend was the opening of firearm deer season in my hometown. It’s a special event for me. It’s a family affair that reinforces our hunting tradition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I’ve participated in opening day hunts in Missouri for the past 15 years (give or take). And before that I participated sporadically for 15-20 years. Now it’s a lead-pipe lock. In early summer we book our flights for the long weekend in early November. No discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can easily label the trip a family event because &lt;a href=&quot;http://gofitgirl.com&quot;&gt;my lovely wife&lt;/a&gt; always goes with me. She doesn’t hunt but she does enjoy lounging around my parents house in her pajamas, curling up with a book and a cup of tea. Just her thing, especially when it’s cold outside. This year was special because she also taught a yoga workshop. Nine attendees paid good money to learn from the master. Very proud of her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past few years my brother, Craig, has joined the hunt along with his oldest son, James. His youngest, Jackson, comes along on the trip but doesn’t participate in the hunt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Craig, James, and I went out both mornings very early. Left the house around 5:30 a.m. A short drive takes us to the farm where we park, load our guns, and walk to our respective deer stands. Arriving and seated in time for first light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year James used the platform stand, Craig squatted in a fence row up near a natural salt lick, and I parked my city-slicker butt in my elevated deer blind on the nose of an open field. My blind has a propane heater  and comfy chair so it’s perfect for me on cold, windy days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re wondering, it’s usually a passive hunt technique. We sit in a tree-stand - or some other kind of elevated position, like a blind - and wait for a deer to walk past. If a buck has substantial antlers it must have at least four points on one side (meaning it must be a relatively mature male deer). But a doe or button/spike buck don’t have any restrictions. If you have the common ‘antler-less’ tag, you can shoot almost anything. Just not an immature buck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw a few deer this year and finally got a pair in the final hours of day two. Usually we hunt only big bucks (more than 8 points) on Saturday and Sunday morning. Then we loosen that rule for Sunday afternoon with intent to put meat on the table for another year. I saw several does on Saturday and Sunday, but only one shootable buck. That one got into the woods before I could get him scoped. The second one I saw was a spike buck (less than three-inch antler, so legal) and he met a clean/quick demise. Same thing goes for the yearling buck James harvested. Venison supply has been replenished for another year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course while all this hunting and lounging goes on my parents are hard at work. Mom cooked all our favorite dishes (we all have several), while dad served as errand runner, dishwasher, general dad duties. He also does all advance planning on hunt logistics. They do a perfect job every time and we head back to the West Coast stuffed to the gills with hospitality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/hunt-report&amp;amp;text=Meat on the table&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Move to Portland</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/portland-awaits"/>
   <updated>2015-11-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/portland-awaits</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our good friend Eric Blumenau came to town for work this week with his girlfriend, Danielle Reichner. We had a great time showing them around town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe I’d had a few too many beers (very likely), maybe they brought it out in me, maybe I was just an idiot. But whatever the reason I found myself trying to convince them to move to Portland. Pretty good jobs, great quality of living, outdoor activities out the wazoo. The whole shebang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably going to be the case for anyone who happens to visit. I can’t help it. I just love this place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only drawbacks I consistently point out are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The weather. We get four seasons. Hot summer (especially this year), cold winter, and two very rainy and inconsistent transitions through fall and spring. It is what it is. Enjoy the good times and deal with the bad.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The lack of diversity. This one is a bit tougher. Portland is overwhelmingly white. I only notice because I used to live in Oakland, one of the most multi-cultural cities on the planet. Now we live alongside a giant loaf of Wonder bread.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that being what it is, Portland is still a great place to relocate. Jobs for tech folks are somewhat plentiful (I’m testing that theory now), the surrounding mountains and beaches are world class, and the booming beer and food scenes are just as good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope I convinced my friends to give PDX a serious look. And if anyone else wants to be convince, just let me know. I’m willing and able.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/portland-awaits&amp;amp;text=Move to Portland&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Deer season</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/deer-season"/>
   <updated>2015-11-11T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/deer-season</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend is our annual pilgrimage to the family homestead in Missouri. The trip always coincides with the opening weekend of firearm deer season, in which I plan to participate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ann always joins too but her activity almost always involves lounging on the couch in a Snuggie the parents purchased special for her use. This year she’s also doing some work: A special yoga workshop. The hometown is usually devoid of yoga classes so this should be a spcial treat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brother is bringing both of his young sons for the hunt, too. So I imagine I’ll have company in my ground blind should the weather turn bad. No way they’re going to last on his elevated platform stand out in the elements. Looking forward to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I keep trying to get my friends &lt;a href=&quot;http://davidsasaki.name&quot;&gt;David&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://cyrusfarivar.com&quot;&gt;Cyrus&lt;/a&gt; to spend some time with me in the deer stand. Hopefully one of those guys will take me up on it one of these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/deer-season&amp;amp;text=Deer season&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Royals are champions</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/royals-win"/>
   <updated>2015-11-03T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/royals-win</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Portland celebration went late into the night on Sunday as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://espn.go.com/mlb/recap?gameId=351101121&quot;&gt;KC Royals won the World Series&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Royals are my original team. I grew up rooting for them, my first big-league game was there, and my first title came in 1985. Then 30 years of small-market problems. Sitting there watching big-market teams (Yankees!!) spend ten times more in payroll and dominate the league.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back on this year’s Series, it’s easy to say the Mets weren’t even the best team in the NL. They just got hot at the right time and wound up in the championship round (where they got dominated, four games to one). The Royals put on an impressive display of aggressive play and resilience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KC was a fun team to watch and a great team to root for. Hats off to them. Several times this week I’ll be cracking open a fresh beer and re-watching the final game. Proud as hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/royals-win&amp;amp;text=Royals are champions&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Portland Code School goes under</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/pcs-closes"/>
   <updated>2015-10-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/pcs-closes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Saturday night I got word via Slack channel that the locks at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.portlandcodeschool.com&quot;&gt;Portland Code School&lt;/a&gt; have been changed and everyone’s on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just completed the flagship course at PCS - the Full Stack Javascript Immersion - so I have skin in the game. The shit part is the fact that there are classes currently in session, and it appears unlikely that any refunds will be offered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once word got out some students and employees immediately formed a channel and &lt;a href=&quot;http://pdxcode.community/&quot;&gt;picked up the communication&lt;/a&gt; in an effort to get the current students set up to finish what they started. That includes generous offers of work space (from graduates and mentors) and teaching assistance from the fantastic staff. All of whom are now out of work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also a hit to folks like myself who have just recently entered the job market. We rely on (and were quite explicitly promised) support in our job search. I’m sure I’ll be fine, but it’s still bad news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/pcs-closes&amp;amp;text=Portland Code School goes under&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Big October</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/big-october"/>
   <updated>2015-10-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/big-october</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;October is typically a busy month in our household. Ann’s birthday, our anniversary, plus almost every other anniversary on the planet. Another big birthday this year belongs to one of my best friends: Ken Conforti. Ken and I were roommates back in the late ’90s. He turns the big 5-0 next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s already a big birthday but this year another great friend of ours - Martin Spanninger - is coming all the way from Germany to celebrate the big day. He’ll spend 10 days in Portland, probably drinking beer and watching American sports on TV the whole time. Fine by me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin and I both went to Portland State and we both know this town pretty well. I’m sure there will also be a trip to the coast or Hood River for a hike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least we have tickets for one Timbers game and a pre-season Blazers game. That should be enough to keep us occupied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/big-october&amp;amp;text=Big October&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Happy birthday to my lovely wife</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/anns-birthday"/>
   <updated>2015-10-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/anns-birthday</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My wife - Ann Chihak Poff - turns 41 on Friday. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://gofitgirl.com/&quot;&gt;her blog&lt;/a&gt; and I’m sure you’ll agree that she may be the most lovely 41-year-old on the planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on this month she and I will celebrate our 12th anniversary. The best 12 years of my life. I can’t imagine life without her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll be celebrating with friends by having drinks/dinner at Montage, her favorite place of all time. Spicy Mac for m’lady.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/anns-birthday&amp;amp;text=Happy birthday to my lovely wife&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Time to play with some Jekyll themes</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/jekyll-options"/>
   <updated>2015-10-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/jekyll-options</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Now that I have the Jekyll basics down, I’m going to start tweaking some theme/template options. I want more stuff in the header, and more obvious linking between this blog and my GitHub profile. I’m not convinced the simple footer does enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So don’t worry if you see things changing day-to-day. It’s all part of the plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/jekyll-options&amp;amp;text=Time to play with some Jekyll themes&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fall is in the air</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/autumn-here"/>
   <updated>2015-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/autumn-here</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Baseball playoffs are about to begin, meaningful football games, and fall colors about hit peak season. I love this time of year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kansas City Royals are in good shape for a playoff run once again. But I don’t expect they’ll do quite as good as last year. It’s still great rooting for my original pro sport team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mizzou has been up/down and are about to be consumed by a QB controversy. The upcoming trip to Athens Georgia probably won’t help matters either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Portland State Vikings are still making noise and are now ranked in FCS. I’ll withhold judgement until after both Montana schools visit Portland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chiefs are maddening, as always. Flashes of great, but always followed by something colossally unfortunate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great time to be a sports fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/autumn-here&amp;amp;text=Fall is in the air&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ciao bella</title>
   <link href="https://blog.curtpoff.com/ciao-bella"/>
   <updated>2015-09-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>https://blog.curtpoff.com/ciao-bella</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our friend Monica visited us this weekend. She and her husband Giovanni (both Italians) are friends of ours from the Bay Area. They were in Ann’s cycle class at the gym and we got to know each other over the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monica came to support Ann, and take all of her cycle and yoga classes over the weekend. She did just that. I think she also enjoyed a little break away from taking care of the family for a few days. Boozy girl brunches and such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a lot of family visits over the summer which was very nice. But Monica is the first ‘friend’ to book a visit. We were very happy to host. Hopefully she can visit again soon and maybe get her workaholic husband to join. We promise to have limoncello on hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-cp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=https://blog.curtpoff.com/ciao-bella&amp;amp;text=Ciao bella&amp;amp;via=cpoff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;share this page with your followers&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cpoff&quot;&gt;follow me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
